so good afternoon folks and now
welcome welcome to our webinar with with
bhargav dasgupta
md and ceo of of icici lombard
uh this is part of the kings of capital
series bhargav is the first
non-lending uh ceo we are inviting
violence so far people wanted to see the
lenders
uh but uh after having done several
lenders we felt that
given the circumstances in which all of
us are living
uh craig and i felt that it would be
appropriate to invite a general
insurer who's uh whose health insurance
policies are being procured and
purchased by millions of
millions of indians so i'll just quickly
set the backdrop i'll introduce bhargav
and then i'll hand over to him for his
remarks on the subject
uh folks feel free to punch in your
questions into the q a box
uh we've got bhargav till six o'clock uh
paige will
curate uh those questions and pose as
many of your questions
to bhargav in the time that we have with
him so let's make the most of it
so so the reason we thought you know we
will have bhargava over to discuss his
thoughts on general insurances
i think as everybody would have felt in
their own lives right uh
uh household savings are on the rise in
the last three four years this was
happening even before
uh the pandemic particularly the
pandemic has introduced
a specific layer of urgency around the
way in which people are buying life
insurance and
and health insurance uh icici lombard is
india's largest
private general insurer and it's been a
leader in this area
uh since 2004 right in fact as taj
pointed out in one of the recent kings
of capital newsletters
over over fi 8 to 20 basically last bar
icici is uh lombard's pat profiter
profit after tax says kagard
compounded at 23 per annum and this is
the remarkable part i say i say robert's
profit has grown at 23
per annum even though the indian general
insurance
profit pool has shrunk over that period
quite remarkable right
leader growing at 23 pack and the rest
of the
market shrinking so it's it's great to
have bhargav here to sort of discuss
quite a remarkable company
is the md and ceo of ilom as we call it
inside marcellus
and he's been in this leadership role
since
he's been with icsa lombard since may
2009.
his career began with the erstwhile
icici limited
vice bank and he's joined icic in 1992
he's held leadership roles across a dive
diverse roles
diverse roles in isi group project
finance corporate banking e-commerce
technology management a subject that we
will discuss
over the course of our chat today uh
holds a post-graduate degree diploma and
management from
i am bangalore and a be in mechanical
engineering from jadofpur
in kolkata so welcome bargain so over to
you sir for your thoughts on what's
happening in icici lombard
how can a firm grow at 23 fat
compounding
in the industry where the pool is
shrinking
thank you thank you sorrow and thank you
for uh having me
uh you know it's a it's a great
privilege to be here uh
i personally follow your posts i have a
lot of regard for the work that you guys
are doing thank you very much
um so uh i think it's interesting that
you talked about the 2008 to 2020
journey so to explain this and maybe
set the context for the future uh i'll
talk about the industry over a
slightly long short view of last 20
years
to explain the industry probably right i
mean and you know that's probably set
the context of as i said what
we believe is happening in the future so
you know this industry while
uh you know it's quite a large industry
you know it's almost two lakh crore
premium
is what we earned as an industry last
year is relatively understood
possibly because the industry you know
we were the first company got listed in
before that there was not too much of a
spotlight on this industry
and from the point that you're making
about personal uh
interest in insurance it wasn't
something that people woke up in the
morning to think about buying
right it was not one of your priority
items that you you know that you thought
of buying
so it was relatively under researched
and understood
industry and that's the problem reason
why i wanted to kind of give you the
long short view to extend the
journey so this industry was opened up
for
you know for private entry in 2000 2001.
before that it was four government
companies which had 100
of the you know sector control and that
year about you know over the
two years 2000 and 2001 about 89
companies came in
but till 2008 which is why you know that
year becomes important
in the in the analysis till 2008 the
pricing for the industry was tariffed
and this is typical global practice you
know in general insurance a lot of
countries
at a stage of development would tariff
their you know premiums because it's a
complex business let the government set
the price
so we had a tariff market in 2008 and in
that you know it was detailed except for
one line of business which is motor
third party liability
the rest of it was all got data now what
happened
uh post 2008 when the deterioration
was that a lot of you know prices really
crashed in certain lines of business
prices crashed by
i mean you wouldn't believe it by more
than 90 percent uh in
in general prices crashed by over 30 40
percent and it stayed low for
uh roughly about 9 10 years till 2018
i would argue and then gradually prices
started going up
why does this happen in in general
insurance and this is typical trend
wherever you see in the world
when the sector is opened up where it is
deteriorative prices come down and then
it starts picking up after four or five
years
because you know this is an industry
where there is no concrete
cost of goods sold so you know you may
write a policy there is no claim
you make you know full premium right but
so and there's natural optimism that
people have in the right policies
and that's the mistake that people make
i think the biggest focus that you know
because learning for gi companies is
that the underwriting aspect which is
you know use data analytics predictive
capability to
price the risk well and then manage the
risk well
is an important element of success and
you know unfortunately for some time
you know i think a lot of players in the
industry never focused on that
for us that was a big focus you know
from the 2008 onwards period because
prior to that prices were very rich it
was direct that wasn't a priority
but as prices crashed by you know as i
said on an average 30-40 percent
we had to do that now as i said this
industry is less understood so
one way of looking at this industry it's
an insurance industry which is a risk
management industry and it is a risk
management industry
the other aspect of this industry is
that it's a float industry
so what happens in this industry is that
you get the premium upfront
claim may happen you know during the
policy period
which is over the next one year which is
traditionally what the you know premium
duration is for
general insurance but in certain cases
as in motor third-party liability for us
claims may happen after six seven years
because the indian law
said that says there are till yeah about
a year and a half back said that
uh a third party claimant can intimate a
claim any time in his lifetime so you
while you're driving the car you have an
accident
you will take your car and get it
repaired immediately so we'll know the
claim immediately
but a pedestrian that you hit on the
road can
decide after 10 years that you know i
got injured and i have
all the proof i will claim now so the
tail as we call it of claims are very
long
and the accounting regulation in india
is that you hold reserves
on a predicted basis for a claim that
may have happened
at that point you don't even know about
this right you'll know about it 10 years
later but using statistical models
usually actually in models you hold a
reserve on a nominal basis
so if the claim today is let's say 100
000 rupees
on an average in our model shows that
the claim duration is about six seven
years
and inflation is double digit so 200 000
rupees today is
will become 200 000 rupees six seven
years later and you hold a nominal
reserve of 200 000 rupees
in a sense different from the typical
lending industry approach
right you don't upfront the future npas
in that manner
so it's a very conservative reserving
and an accounting
uh you know model that we have in india
when you do that
it depresses your profit for the period
absolutely and depresses your
roe it at you know depressive and book
value
you know capital and also it creates a
float because you're sitting on this
money for six years right and if you
manage that float well which is why i
call it a float management business as
well
you can deliver a good return on equity
uh you know
relative to some of the other place so
if you see you know for us the
last uh you know 13 years that we talked
about we've had a
category of over 23 largely because you
know if you look at our
uh investment float to network is
roughly about four times today it was
less earlier
and we've delivered about eight nine
percent return on that float and if you
run your investment book
uh sorry the the insurance book at you
know a reasonable cost of that float as
in the underwriting losses are not very
high
you can very easily deliver that rv so
that's the fundamental model
now also to step back and explain the
structure of the industry
uh you know other lines of bfsi's as i
said you know more understood
you know everyone is looking to save
money everyone is looking to buy a car
everyone is
looking for a you know uh you know
gaining the stock market investing in
mutual fund
so again you know as an at an individual
level also you understand and connect
with an industry a bit more
now this industry is in a sense a unique
uh
you know industry within bfsi where we
don't compete with any other part of the
industry
bfsi sector so a mutual fund and a live
company may be competing for the same
same uh you know savings pool a bank an
nbfc is competing for the same
you know asset customer we don't compete
with any other part of the bfsi space so
that's another reason why probably the
sector is relatively
in a sense isolated but also creates an
advantage for good players in this
industry because
you're competing within your sector with
your
you know competitive set and if you now
look at the structure of the industry
um as i said when it started the four
psus
uh you know multi-line general insurance
companies there were eight or nine of us
who came in in 2008 nine
and that's how the structure of the
industry was still roughly about 207.8
and then a bunch of companies started
coming in
almost every year one two three
companies would come in today we have 34
companies
the last set of forum companies came in
in 2017
since then there's not been a new
entrant in this industry
and within that you know that cohort of
about 34 odd companies
i would say i would put them in four
bucket or three buckets let's say one is
a psus
uh you know bit challenged now because
of the aggression of the
2008 to 2018 has kind of hurt their
balance sheets
solvency is under pressure so they need
capital infusion
you know from the government and there's
been a talk of government increasing
capital but there is only a limit of how
much capital can be infused
the second is among those original eight
nine companies there are three or four
companies
which i believe have built a sustainable
business and then there's a long
tail of you know small you know more
recent companies will come in some of
them have done well but
not all of them have done well and they
are kind of in a small you know kind of
competing at the at the
at the edges so our sense is that you
know this industry is kind of
getting rapidly consolidated and i think
this over impact is probably going to be
felt even more
in terms of driving towards safety and
quality and and scale uh
you know going ahead and some of these
better players will uh
gain a larger share of the profit pool
of the industry so let's see
you know in a sense maybe you know 30
000 feet back down to the industry
and coming to your point on what we
think will happen uh sector by sector so
you know in terms of growth the first
eight years when the pricing was
as i said you know uh tariffed and it
was reasonably rich
the industry grew at about 17 kagger in
those
eight years if you see the next 13 years
and that includes last years of almost
you know single digit growth
the industry is grown at close to 16
canada about 15.8
now you know if you take out that you
know five percent growth that we had
last year it's again close to seventeen
percent growth uh
sixteen point uh decimal point growth
for the industry
so in spite of price correction that i
talked about
this industry is continue to grow at
that pace right
and that's largely driven by the
clear change in mindset of customers
which is where
what you are trying to you know you are
starting with into the what are we
seeing in terms of customer
uh you know changes in customer
you know insights and behavior clearly i
mean you know if you
ask me six seven years back health
insurance was a push sale right you have
to go out and convince people that you
need to buy a health insurance
and by the way another interesting
statistic if you look at the total
health care
spending in this country roughly two
thirds is out of pocket about 63 64 i
mean this number you know changes a
little bit here and there but
ballpark about two thirds of it out of
it is out of pocket
which means government doesn't pay for
it insurance doesn't pay for it
if an event happens you you know sell
assets or you know
take loans from you know you know or
take grants uh from
family members and and or your saving
tip into savings and and take care of
the bill
if you see global you know benchmarks
this is you know like the least
developed countries
you know this is absurd saharan africa
right this is really poor i mean you
know
60 to 65 is very very low most countries
would have
you know 70 80 paid for by either
insurance or
government provided healthcare so that
itself is creating a pool for health
insurance an event like this
unfortunate unfortunate event but makes
people realize the importance of
protection similarly for motor insurance
what we understand is that based on data
that
over the last three four years is now
coming together where the central
government has created a
centralized database of registered
vehicles on the road which we didn't
have
something like this a few years back and
the insurance industry has created a
registered database of insured vehicles
we are seeing more than 50 vehicles on
the road flying without an insurance
now large part proportion of that may be
two-wheeler
and it's typically that you know why and
by the way again it's a law of the land
that you have to have a third-party
liability insurance when you're driving
a vehicle but in spite of that
and again that's changing supreme court
pass some judgment which will change
which will change it
i think compliance is changing with more
digitization more data and more
availability of these cross linkages
between industries
databases for the you know for the
pulley system also to catch
you know people without insurance so
some of these things are changing
similarly what we are saying if you look
at the other two components so if you
look at our industry there is motor
insurance there is health insurance
there is
corporate pnc you know typical you know
property and casualty that you know
globally is seen as a
big part and lastly crop and crop
you know i won't spend time we don't
write crop but rest of it pnc again you
know
huge amount of under insurance um
you know if you see this time when covet
happened globally there was a big debate
on should insurance pay for
and you know this non-damage business
interruption loss
you know what to interact what insurance
industry pays traditionally
is for if there is a natural calamity or
a fire or a flood in your premise
because of which your business is
interrupted we pay for the damage to
your property
as also the loss of revenue right you
know minus your cost et cetera so that
is called business interruption
now globally there are non-damaged
business interruption covers which are
popular
so you don't have to wait for a damage
to your property maybe for some other
reason you know you have to
stop not something that you could
control then the industry would pay for
the bi claims
now that problem didn't arise in india
because no one had those those products
have never been popular
uh you know liability insurance you know
directors in office of liability
insurance
it's quite shocking how many of the
listed firms don't even have the under
policy i'm just giving some
uh you know anecdotal uh you know
examples so sector by sector there is a
huge
underpenetration and if you look at the
aggregate number
in every sector in india is under
penetrate so when you throw a global
number
it may not be relevant but if you
compare with china china's
insurance density is two hundred dollars
per capita
we are nineteen dollars per capita
that's how stark it is wow one tenth of
china
one tenth of china into the insurance
density per capita insurance period
so all of this the the recent upsurge in
interest
in health insurance um uh uh
and the whole surgeon interest in in
protecting one's family
do you reckon this is this will pass
when covert passes
or do you think this is here to stay
it's a structural shift is there any way
to
get a grip on how long this interest
sustains
so i'll tell you what we saw last year
and that probably reflects the mindset
right
what we saw last year is that the demand
for health insurance started picking up
from
april may and reached a peak in q2 of
last year
and then it started tapering off and
that you know
in a sense probably partially answers
your question the elevated demand that
we saw i mean these were
you know very rapid growth times you
know 50 60 growth in that period
suddenly dropped to an you know drop but
didn't drop to the original traditional
level
that we used to see so my sense is that
whenever there is a crisis there is a
demand for insurance that picks up
but it also lifts there's a structural
shift up
in terms of the aggregate demand that it
creates you know so this
is the kind of growth that we are seeing
today may not
continue next year but relative to what
we saw two years back there is a
structural
increase in the demand for health
insurance anecdotally what we are seeing
is
one people who never had any health
insurance are of course you know buying
more
but what is even more i think personally
interesting is
until about two years back we used to
convince we used to go out and tell our
customers that a five lakh insurance
cover is nothing today
i mean you go to a hospital for you know
five days you'll spend
spend much more than that in the big
cities so we should
try to tell them and we've had
situations a customer with a you know
has a mercedes but has a three lag
insurance
right so what's the value of a
three-legged insurance for a membership
is you know driver
so that segment i mean we had more
almost 30 40 percent of those
you know customers saying can you upsell
me here or can you give me a 10 lakh
cover
i have a five lakh cover give me a 10
lakh cover so there is a there is
definitely a shift in terms of
demand for some higher some insured that
has happened and i think that's a
structural shift because once you bought
a 10 lakh cover you're not going
to go back to five lakh cover but it's
also increase the demand for
uh health insurance as a category now as
i said
it may not remain at that same elevated
level but relative to what it was there
is a structural
increase and just to sort of flip the
question on its head now this
there's all a lot of a lot of our
clients ask us
that look you have icici lombard in the
kings of capital portfolio but
hey won't there be a deluge of covet
claims that will
that will take away whatever premiums
they're writing uh is there a way for
you to statistically model
uh uh what the incidence or claims will
be i know it's still you know we don't
yet know whether third wave will come or
not but is there any way to model this
look uh we do model it and you know
they're not to say that the model is
perfect because this model you know no
one gets this model right
is is uh is our experience um having
said that i'll tell you what happens for
us
right uh so if you look at the health
insurance pie
for us it's really we are a slightly
smaller share of health insurance
compared to the industry category so
industry has
standalone health companies which are
only health insurance right and they
have a larger
piece of the health by if you look at
the overall industry construct we have a
relatively lower share of
uh health insurance within health
insurance there are
let's say three categories one is the
social insurance where we don't play
which is the government funded insurance
schemes where we don't
have any exposure it's its premium is
inadequate
the second is the employer employee
which is the corporate sector buying
policies for their employees
where we have a normal market share we
have slightly less than a normal market
share but we have a reasonable market
share
the third is retail which individuals
buy insurance right
and within that there are two categories
one is benefit plans these are
you know we call them benefit plans
these are basically fixed benefit
uh plans for specified diseases so these
are critical
illnesses let's say you buy a cancer
policy or you buy
a policy which covers you know 33
uh you know high uh cost procedures
you know illnesses which lead to high
cost let's say you know a renal failure
or a cancer or a uh you know or a cabg
you know heart etc so some of those
things
but they pay only for that those 33
elements it doesn't pay for generic
hospitalization
so they are called the benefit policies
and the other categories indemnity
policy which is
as the word indicates it indemnifies the
cause cost that you incur in a hospital
so that covers anything that you know
for whatever reason you may be in a
hospital farm
we will cover it including for covet so
now for us as a nice as i said
i said our retail health portfolio is
slightly small for a you know historic
reason we can get into that if you want
to
uh we are building it out but still it's
you know we have a two to three percent
share
in the market share unless unlike our
seven percent market share overall
and within the retail health we are much
more or we have
traditionally been a much more of a
benefit company and less of an indemnity
company
so for us it's not a big problem for the
industry for the standalone health
company this is definitely a big problem
because no one anticipated this no one
priced this
uh in some of the markets like us you
know spain you know australia
insurers have basically said this
pandemic was not was an exclusion
we will not pay government is paying for
this healthcare cost in india as an
industry
we are bearing this cost the other thing
that we see when this covet happens is
again as a
from a portfolio perspective we have
motors other policies etc motor claim
ratio comes down
and and health goes up and within health
the medical management or the elective
surgeries go down
and only the covert hospitalization goes
up so on balance
we are actually better off from a clinic
we are actually uh unfortunate to say
that as an insurance company today but
it's just so that
it's such happen it so happens given our
portfolio makes
that we don't uh have any uh body on the
covet
standalone health companies would have a
big problem so so
just to now move away from uh the
covalent health and
think more structurally right uh i
suspect
in circles like ours and the people who
are attending today right affluent
people on zoom
marcellus clients and so on i suspect
the penetration is already
penetration of your products is already
pretty pretty
evolved pretty mature it's the
smaller towns and smaller towns and
cities and perhaps the lower income
strata
can you give us a sense of how quickly
or
not the penetration there is coming
through there must be a way of for you
to measure that given how much
technology you guys have
is the penetration story that one tenth
of china story
is the is the remedy of that is the
remediation of the
one tenth of china story working out or
is it science or mukherjee
are buying more and more eye long
products you know you would be surprised
sorry so
yes intuitively you would think that
everyone here has adequate insurance
cover
the fact is in this period the number of
my
you know acquaintances and friends who
reached out asking for enhanced cover
has been remarkable wow and people have
as i said
you know health policy from their
corporate you know company provider
health policy people think that's good
enough they don't worry about
it so people are now buying cup of
covers you know i have a three dollar
cover from my company
let me buy a policy which has a
three-line be reputable and you know i
buy a top-up cover
about that that's one secondly
if you look at traditional insurance or
insurance health insurance anywhere in
the world
you will find that health insurance pays
for the entire continuum of care
from your dental expenses to a visit to
a you know
dermat to a visit to a gp your pharmacy
bills
everything is covered in insurance and
if you think about the total cost of
health care
you know the hospitalization cost which
is the only thing that we pick up is
again
roughly one third of the total health
care spends in the country so we have
not even touched that two-third
right we only focusing on the sliver of
the
ipd which is a health care cost in a
hospital and within that there is an
under penetration
uh because of our under insurance people
have insurance but it's under insurance
compared to
this cost so to me the opportunity in
across strata
is is significant both in terms of full
coverage
uh and there's a reason why as an
industry we couldn't you know cover
uh outpatient and you know all these
dentistry etc
at a stage of evolution that we wear if
you increase the premium
the attractiveness of the product comes
down so
you know you have to for some time maybe
give a restricted product and you know
make people
consume part of it and then get you know
then people come in and understand the
value of the product and it increases
number one number two
controlling abuse uh in a outside a
network
uh hospital in a in a opd setup
is tremendously challenging even in the
hospital it's a challenge
outside it is even more of a challenge
and we couldn't do it
unless we built a tech you know platform
which
created an ecosystem which we've now
done i mean as isis number we created
one about couple of years back so that's
that's how we are going into that
segment so to answer your question that
that segment is also underpaid
but your larger point about the rural
market
is still something way away is my sense
i mean there is clearly an increase that
we are seeing so for example one of the
things that we did about
three years back was we set up these
virtual offices which is
no branch office with a sales guys a guy
with a
you know tech stack basically working
off uh you know distributors offices and
homes
uh so as to keep our costs down we have
over 840 of those uh
we set up a bit more than that but some
of them were underperforming we needed
out now it's about 8 40
and we'll invest again in the next round
in that but that 840 is
the three is growing much faster than
the rest of the business
right on a small base so uh so we still
have a long way to go in the
rural markets but again this event this
event has probably changed perception a
bit
so what you're saying is that the big
metros plus say the district towns will
still be 90 percent of your
yeah of your business right exactly now
this
this technology please right in your
career pre-i
i i long career i noticed that i said
itself you've done a technology role
and and your tech savviness has
obviously been uh uh
the firm's tech savviness has been very
prominent i think many of
uh in the pre-covered world many of us
took uh uh ola ruber cabs
where part of the prompt was you know do
you want to insure yourself from for
this journey
courtesy i say i see a lombard now this
aspect
of bringing technology to insurance in a
way what bajaj finance has done in the
nbfc world and arguably and uh
you know this is a non-icici company
what hdfc life has done in life
insurance
you guys have done in general insurance
where did the impetus
for this come where did the impactors
for this come and how materially do you
think this contributes to that 21
roe that you guys are able to post uh
which is uh
the best in class number uh so tech
inspiration and contribution to roe
please
okay so inspiration you know sort of uh
honestly speaking
if anyone as a group as a financial
services group was the leader
in tech was icsa right you know maybe
some parts of isis has fallen behind but
uh you know if you go back to the early
days of ice
sorry the first atm in the country you
guys yeah
exactly i mean first you know online
banking uh
was again you know icc bank so uh so
anyway so this has
been part of the learning is part of our
development right
uh you know i remember when mr kamath
was running icc bank he used to believe
that
business managers should be think of
themselves as technology managers
and that's very progressive thinking
from from those days time
and personally you know i thought that
thought process appealed to me
uh but coming but there's a context
right i mean if you look at a gi
business
as i said in 2008 prices dropped by 90
right and i'll give you a just a
two statistic and then i'll talk about
some of the sectors so if you look at
icsa lombard in 2008 we had roughly
eighteen and a half thousand bit more
than eighteen thousand
ft's ft's doesn't mean agents are not
including agents full-time employees
maybe employees or uh contract staff uh
you know who are working full-time for
us a bit more than eighteen thousand
cut to today we have a bit more than ten
thousand plus
our business has grown five x our policy
count has grown about eight x
in this field now we had to do this
because when prices
correct at the level that it did you
have to
you know kind of squeeze water from
stone right because you have to keep
your cost under so much of control
uh to be able to survive uh you know in
that in that environment
now initially it was cost and
convenience and very rapidly we realized
the
the value of digital data
and before i go into digital details
just give you one more example so for
example
uh in 2012 we started focusing on
building up a two-wheeler insurance
business
we were it was there it was not that we
were right not writing but it was not it
was not scaled up
and the traditional conventional logic
in the industry was that two wheeler
insurance is unviable because
i mean you know a 7 800 rupee policy
imagine issuing a policy right
you'll eat you know 50 of the cost into
the cost of servicing the policy
so you can't you know think of running
that business if you don't completely
digitize the process
so we said okay let's think of doing
this differently and we
tied up with petrol pumps you know again
on an ipad or a laptop someone on the on
the
on the ground was issuing a policy while
you're filling your bike that was our
promise
before you can fill your bike and pay
the bill our insurance policy will be
issued
and it is it is non-trivial in terms of
trying to do this in a remote
area because of connectivity challenges
etc so there's a lot of things that we
have to do to even you know
build some of these businesses uh coming
to your question on uh you know what it
does today the way we look at it is that
of course the cost convenience all that
is you know par for the course
but the biggest advantage today is the
because we've digitized over the years
uh today we are
able to think of one digitizing the next
level
but more importantly the data that we've
built created over
the years is to us one of our biggest
advantage
so uh i'll give you one small example so
when you have a motor uh policy and you
forget to renew the policy right what do
we do as a traditionally as an insurance
company
we send a survey to check whether there
is any damage during that period so
suppose your policy was
due on first may you woke up on 15 may
and said no can you give me a policy
i want to know that you didn't have an
accident during this 15 days because
otherwise you'll be
you know gaming me right so uh what do
we do we send a
server to check whether the card is
damaged or not
we were working on a virtual inspection
process right
you know using your tablet you could do
a claims normal claims adjudication we
don't
not necessarily send a survey you do
your survey using your phone
so we said now we've got a lot of images
a lot of data
right and you know in any case we had
started tablets based service
surveys from 2012 onwards we have a lot
of images of uh you know damaged
vehicles
so we use that to build an ai model to
allow
you know people to do the inspection of
the car just take eight photographs and
we guide the person and you know the ai
engine figures out whether there's a
damage to the vehicle or not
it saves us cost it's great convenience
similarly for health
um and i'll give you some example of
covert you know so if you look at the
instaspec data which is the virtual
inspection this is not the
you know the breaking survey is a
different part the virtual inspection
we were about doing about 25 of the
cases in march before covet
march 2020 exit last year we were doing
about 60
wow that's the kind of progress that
we've seen in one year
some of it being forced and it's just a
great you know opportunity to
push these uh these uh you know take
steps
these are here to stay i mean you know
i'll give you one more example of health
for example
so we use data of the past to authorize
health
uh you know approval authorization to
the hospital
for our group customers without any
doctor
intervention earlier doctor would say
the you know case file and say okay it's
authorized you can start today we do it
you know through the through a ai ml
engine again the number was 30
peak of it the number is about 65
today that's the way it scaled up now
this we couldn't have done without
the you know automation and the
digitization of the past
because we had the data of the past to
build these engines and
if you can keep on working on this
engine and build on it which we
obviously
are doing you know we're kind of
building on each of this i think the
the it becomes tougher and tougher to
play a catch-up game
right right so you're saying the data
that you have your competitors don't
have
right as a result your underwriting is
better your claims
uh uh claims ratios are better superior
uh your profitability improves you then
you invest that money and earn better
and better returns that's the thought
process now it's okay it's the execution
issue thereafter
so so i'll hand over to page uh now
before i hand over i'll give you an
anecdote relating to motor insurance
and this will explain one of the reasons
why i migrated to india so when i was 18
i took my dad's car i was insured to
drive that car and i drove it into a
rubbish truck
right this was in england and the car
was a write-off
but the consequence of that was for the
next 13 years in the uk i paid
very high uh insurance policy rates
right so by the time i left the uk
my annual motor insurance premium was
more than the value of
my car right so when i came to india
nobody asked me this question
right did you wreck a car in the uk so i
still benefit because no
motor insurer asks me about my wreck as
a 18 year old
and it's a huge privilege of living in
this country to get more
[Laughter]
so insurance throw you out of uk that's
interesting
on this topic we've got a few questions
on what do you make of
the new digital or online only general
insurers
which have come in over the past four
five
uh will they be able to you know
transform this industry
over the next decade or so yeah i think
that's uh so
you know that's a good question and uh
and i want i think we should pay some
attention to this
because if i look at this you know when
i played the uh
story about the history of this industry
from 2007 a bunch of companies kept
coming in
till 2017. there's no new company that
is coming after 2017.
except for one company everyone till now
has had a me too strategy
uh me too strategy in the sense that go
to the same channels you know
with the same product you know
proposition and try to
compete with the established players
which you know
i mean you can figure out what the
consequence of that is
today there is only one company and
there are many companies who talk
digital but
today only one company is trying to be
completely digital
right there is some other companies
which say that they're digital but
they're exactly in the same dealerships
exactly in the same uh you know channels
doing reinsurance doing crop
everything else right now
i've always said that you know let's
look at the two new companies one is
digital
completely the other is digital but
we're doing
things that the way that everyone else
is and i've always said the company
which is doing the things that everyone
else is
probably will initially have a better
success because today
it is you know and i'll explain the
industry structure
uh today it is very difficult for a pure
play digital company to come in and
compete in a meaningful way
today now that doesn't mean things won't
change over 10 years
so if i look at a differential strategy
as i said only one company has come up
with a differentiated strategy and
that's
trying to build a pure play online
business now why do i say
it's a tough uh you know ask
because we've been you know also we have
a digital
business from 2004 five you know we
started issuing policies back then
we about two and a half years back we
carved out our digital division into a
separate we called a company within a
company we called it digital one
which has a separate board separate hr
policies separate
structures separate team which is
engineering you know actuarial
underwriting everything separate right
so we try to create a company within a
company so we kind of have the
experience of running a
digital business and the cost of digital
so what happens in india
so when you buy a car the first policy
that you buy
it's it gets sold to you from the dealer
typically you go to a car they will give
you a list price in the list price there
will be a line item which says insurance
and you will usually be you know one
invoice you won't even realize that
there's a separate
piece and you know the dealer will say
don't worry i will take care of
all the convenience service etc so if a
claim happens just call me
it's very convenient so rough almost
almost
entire fresh policy sale happens
in the uh premise of the dealer and the
dealer does a lot of hard work to retain
that customer for a couple of years
right and then
maybe two three years the customer uh
you know
then is you know the connect with the
dealer reduces he's also willing to
get his vehicle repaired in some other
uh you know smaller
garage he doesn't have to doesn't need
to go back to the same dealer
but the first two three years he's very
you know passionate about his car he
doesn't want to go to a small shop he
goes to the same dealer
so there's a very strong bond after
three years so that is when the
insurance bond also breaks you
start you know researching online maybe
buying from an agent etc
and then after another two three years
you buy a new car
traditionally in india typically for
five years later you buy a new car after
five years you buy a new car
and you go back to that same cycle so
that's the structural challenge for a
pure player digital company on
motorcycle today on the health side
uh because you know the the let me
complete this are possible when you
procure a customer online in the first
year it it takes two to three years to
break you in this is a huge cost of
sourcing the first year
and then you to kind of deflate over a
period so that's the that's the only
challenge that
pure digital has and now with this
supreme court uh
you know decision arm which is in my
opinion very very positive decision
because of the under
in under penetration point that i made
so with uh
with two wheelers it's five years uh so
the tp policy is any way out even if
you're coming in after
three years you're only going for the od
policy and similarly for private car
three years the tp policy is out you're
only going for the od policy
so now you're chasing an even smaller
pipe as a digital player
because the tp policy has anyway gone
for the first year
coming to health health needs a
tremendous amount of engagement
and as of now i have not found anyone
including us
we have not cracked the code of complete
online so all of our
us is basically doing assisted online
you know the customer come in somewhere
you know our telephone will
happen and we will close the close the
same and
there's a fundamental reason we we do a
lot of research with customers
there is a reason why customers need
some amount of
personal uh advice it's a it's a very
advisory model as of now on uh
pictures and the the indemnity part
which is a big part of the healthy
so those are the two big detail pieces
the one thing that can go online which
is already gone online is travel but
it's a small piece of the market
so i think this is just worth
elaborating what bhargav is saying is
because the supreme court is mandating
that at the point of purchase
you have to have three years of of third
party cover
and at the point of purchase typically
all of us when we buy new cars the
the showroom is basically selling the
policy to us or intermediating the
policy
therefore the online guy gets cut out of
that the online manufacturer
gets cut out of the action and in that
regard the supreme courts dictat
allows the or the conventional
incumbents to
enhance their position enhance their
market share to the detriment of the
online challenges
that's a very interesting point actually
back to you
one of the questions you've got is on
the investment side so you can work
with management underwriting uh but
investment is
most important and functional especially
for a general insurance of the float
management
uh how is it that icici lombard over
it's almost not 20 years not seen even a
single night off
on its investment so i guess we've been
a bit lucky
um but so if you look at our investment
asset so today it's roughly about 31 000
crores
uh roughly about 80 percent is in bonds
uh
typically it ranges between 85 to maybe
75 in that range roughly 80 81 percent
is in bonds
of which a large chunk is in government
bonds even from a
regulatory perspective over 30 percent
has to be in government once
uh and rest of it is in corporate bonds
and
as of now about 12 13 is in equity and
rest we keep in some alternate assets
and
largely liquidity even five percent in
largely in cash
for claims etc so the approach that
we've taken because
the bond book is the material part of
the book um you know
equity we have uh another strategy and
thankfully we've done reasonably well uh
but on the bond side if you make
mistakes it's a big cost right
so our approach has been that
we take duration calls we take
interested calls you know we take a view
on interest rate
we do that and we've done that over the
last you know 20 years
we always take duration calls using
government securities we never take
duration call using corporate bonds
because that's not worth it right so you
know any way you're
taking an interested call so focus using
the use the uh you know
government securities on the corporate
bonds when we invest
we do not invest below double we are
typically on
typically invest triple in double a plus
but we do not
invest below double a uh and even double
is a very small component of our
business
and we do not invest based on credit
rating
only uh we of course look at crediting
but that's not the only filter
that we look at when we are investing in
now why do we do this because
uh and this is based on data and
research but our strong conviction
uh you know the investment team has been
there with us from for 20 years and you
know
some and they're originally from icsa so
we've seen the market market
data shows and our experience says that
the
risk premium that the market gives
for lower rating is not adequate for the
incremental risk in india
the so what i mean by that if you you're
getting you know six percent for a
you know triple a bond and you get five
point you know
sorry six point seven percent for a
single a that point seven percent is not
adequate for the risk
the the risk premium that should be
there for a for
for the you know difference in rating
that's that's our point of view
and secondly um so so
and secondly as i said we don't just
look at the rating
you know company we have been in the
sector so we have a
way to sense whether we trust the
management in the governance et cetera
and we play safe
and what that has done is you know as
you rightly said
we've not had a single corporate bond
which is defaulted in our history
and we've not had a single corporate
bond which is even delayed interest
payment in art history
uh and i think it's just we believe that
playing safe on the bond market makes
is more uh it's a much more value
creating strategy over long term
and if you look at our investment
portfolio including the equity and the
overall portfolio
uh over the last 20 years we've returned
close to ten percent about nine point
seven nine point eight percent return
uh throughout this uh this history
right right uh one of the questions is
around the recent acquisition
uh could you share what is the thought
process what went
uh behind this acquisition in terms of
was it
financial metrics in addition to that
the distribution which
the new acquisition would give out and
historically as well you evaluated
health insurance also in the past
what is it uh which goes behind the
decision of you know finally pulling the
trigger
yeah so uh you're right we've looked at
the so the way we've looked at uh mna
has been
there has to be some amount of
complementarity or
because of the synergy we you know we
add some new distributor and
also the synergy benefit plays out in
terms of creating value for our
shareholders
so we've looked at many transactions in
the past i mean
there are enough transactions markets
float around and most of them typically
come to us
and in the past we yes we i think
in the papers we looked at one health
insurance platform very very you know
very closely uh but you know someone
else
were willing to pay more than what we
were willing to pay and that's why it
didn't happen
in this case it was a uh you know it was
a you know in a sense of
one-to-one conversation curated
transaction so what happened
uh you know early days of the covet
lockdown
uh is that we had our call was that
the market this industry will
consolidate far further and the
big will become bigger and stronger and
this was ripe for consolidation
and when we look at consolidation there
is
of course the new capabilities that you
can look at let's say a pure play health
company
or you look at a mid-size uh you know
company which you can
integrate and create value so when we
look at you know this entity
uh bhaji uh if you look at this company
it was set up in 2008 but for the first
five
six years uh you know it had a mixed
experience in terms of what they
delivered
and then they had a change in management
about four five years back a new team
came in
and uh we saw that they were doing a
bunch of good things i mean in terms of
building out the right distribution
tying up with the right
you know bank actions partners building
the uh
base for uh you know a value creating
business
but they were sub-scale you know three
three or three thousand two hundred
close of premium
you know the investment that they were
making uh it was difficult for them to
deliver you know a profitability
so if you look at the you know if you
look at the 20 20 numbers for them
which is what we saw when we looked at
the transaction
their loss ratio was 78 expense ratio is
42 percent
uh and a lot of it is because of the
subsequent nature
and the other thing that we always we
did look at in this case was
a lot of um in a sense uh the soft the
governance governance related issues
we like their accounting their reserving
their culture
a good bunch of people good team uh and
that's why we said and you know it was
it was kind of a reasonable size it was
not very large not very small
so it was right in the you know the
sweet spot in a sense and that's what uh
why we looked at this transaction
there's a 42
expense ratio uh obviously when you come
together you'll save a lot of uh
unnecessary money that there are
spending
just to quickly just uh ask a question
on that so so although there's a
there's actually a lot of literature um
in academia and the plenty of case
studies done
on on your sort of industry that this
sort of industry necessarily ends up
being dominated by
you know one or two maximum three
players right so so
uh one of my professors in college a man
called john sutton
john sutton wrote a famous paper in 1992
that any industry where
and in tangible assets uh uh uh
intellectual property uh
intangible assets is a critical driver
of success you will end up with a
two-player
industry now if you guys genuinely have
superior
data and better underwriting
and you are combining that with superior
skills in managing your float
you presumably end up uh doing a really
good job
does that therefore imply that through
your
efficiency and comparative strengths and
perhaps through such
future acquisitions you end up
consolidating this industry
it's a possibility i mean i'm not saying
that we are uh you know kind of thinking
about a
m a uh you know every waking hour
uh so our thought process is that you
know right now you know this transaction
is awaiting the final approval
once that happens we want to we've done
a lot of hard work in this
you know eight ten months in terms of
preparing for the integration
whatever is legally allowed within that
bonds we've
prepared for it and i think the next 12
months will be
execution and we want to ensure that
what we had assumed in terms of our
you know synergy advantages both in the
revenue side as also in the
cost side we are able to actually
deliver so that's the focus
having said that we are very open you
know as we've always said i think this
industry will
you're absolutely right we believe i
mean you know i'm a bit more generous
maybe four or five companies what i've
been
saying that we need we'll end up with
four five companies which will capture
most of the value
and you could wait for others to
consolidate it
you know companies don't die in india
right so something happens you know
they get they get bought out they get
you know change of management maybe a pe
comes in
when the current shareholder struggles
to provide more capital
and more capital coming in creates you
know unnecessary
you know pressure in terms of
competitive intensity and as it
consolidates it becomes a stronger and
more robust industry
and you know the industry is also able
to invest and serve customers better
so uh so it will happen the question is
do you want to
be a moving force behind it or do you
want to
play on the side we believe as a leader
you know it makes sense for us to play a
more active role
right back to you
um a few questions around
because this has become more competitive
in terms of as an industry in terms of
pricing recently on the motor side
do you see competitive intensity on
some of the tps tariffs but on the motor
road side
increasing of late uh from the private
general insurance space
uh and you think that this is something
which has happened
in the past as well therefore uh it is
sort of cyclical and competition comes
and goes away and you'll be able to
manage
segments so i your voice broke for a
second page i understood the question as
you know do you see pricing correcting
in od and this has been
a pattern in the past sometimes
competition intensity increases
and whether it'll settle here okay so uh
to to look at it again from a you know
uh kind of a long horizon from 2008
onwards we've seen the cyclic layout
many times
before we were listed it was not seen by
the market but we've seen players coming
in particularly in 2789 there were a
bunch of players that came in
and the initial strategy for most of
them was to
get very aggressive in the motorcycle
because it's the easiest segment to
focus on right to build
it's a large you know largest segment in
the industry and you can go to a dealer
and you know
you know throw up throw some uh you know
price or or commission uh you know
dolly and you can get some business
right so this has been we've seen it
many times and whenever this happens for
two to three years these companies
gain a bit of market share then struggle
because it's not a sustainable strategy
and at least our approach has been while
it's a franchise we don't want to let go
of our franchise so we stay
invested in the dealership we you know
kind of balance our portfolio
uh during those times and we believe in
a sense
like you know you know in the on the
investment side you should be
contradicted even in the business side
if you can you should be a bit more
contrived
that's what we've been trying to do now
more recently last two years
i would say pre-covered there was
clearly a pressure that was being felt
in the industry and
our senses that market would have
started repricing a bit we were
starting to have those conversations and
then because covet happened
and frequency of claims did drop right
because of the lockdown etc there was no
need for a price increase
and you know it's a competitive industry
if there's no need
uh the prices won't go up and again by
the end of last year the pressure was
building up
we as a company had actually you know
told quite a few oems that we are going
to increase prices
next year we did do some tweaking here
and there
uh and then again the second wave
happened uh and again the same story has
been played out
my sense is that when things normalize
uh we are hoping
you know again we are hoping no one
knows that the third wave won't happen
uh but moment things normalize there
will be a tremendous pressure for price
correction
and this is a typical cycle that we see
in the industry because
uh you know for quite a few players
uh particularly on the health side they
will have some challenges this time
round this wave is much worse than the
first wave
and then on top of it if the motor side
doesn't support it will be
challenging for some players
right historically being
able to switch segments whether it be
exiting out of crop
or entering into fire recently
you've been able to switch segments uh
pretty quickly
how is it that you've been able to
support these are we generating
opportunities uh across these segments
while
most other players they've not been
maybe so limited
i guess it's to do with the uh maybe the
mindset
or the incentives i mean question is
what are people being measured on
and what uh organization capability have
they built
first i don't want to comment but if you
see the organization capability
um you know one of the things that we do
as a company is our underwriting
sales actuary our finance and i we sit
together with a
with our motor portfolio every month
right and we
review the portfolio and uh discuss
calls
and and we take calls which is more
from a sustainability perspective that
you know at the end of the day if you
don't deliver a
reasonable roa there's no point you know
doing that business
but these are franchises right so you
have an agent who's
giving you that business or a dealer
which is giving you that business so
you don't exit that franchise where we
do take calls
as an example that you given crop you
know that's not really a franchise
business in the sense it's a bidding
business every year
if you have the capability you bid and
you go and uh you know
win that business so there you can take
a more
uh binary call right uh but for
franchise business you have to take a
very calibrated call
what i mean by a calibrate call is that
you say that okay you know this
particular
distributor i will reduce my market
share to 10
but i'll stay invested now so that's
what we do and the
the challenge is for the team because
you know we can decide that in sitting
in corporate office in bombay but for
the team it's
definitely very challenging but i think
that's a cultural thing that we've got
that that's got built over the years
because people know that we
will focus on profitable business they
know that we don't want to vacate a
relationship we
we value a relationship with our data
distributed like
anything so we have a frank conversation
with
with the dealer saying that this is my
problem um
most times it works some sometimes it
doesn't work one time most times
it works so just to sort of take a a
a cue on that part of so you know one
[Music]
positive way to look at ilom and in a
way uh to think about ilom is
may be a significant part of ilom
success and the very impressive roe and
the pad growth that we discussed at the
outset of the conversation
the icici bank the might of icici's
distribution might
has you know rubbed off positively on on
you guys
uh the company that you're acquiring for
instance didn't have that sort of
distribution uh most of your rivals
don't have natural distribution now
credit to icsi bank for
for building ilong but i long clearly
benefits from that
how much of your success do you reckon
is because of the distribution might
of the icici banking machine look at
the beginning you know first is a brand
right i mean the fact that we have the
icc brand itself is a huge
uh positive uh for us to build you know
and there's enough research which says
that
in india financial services brands
usually do well in other adjacent
financial services business right
so that itself is a big big positive so
uh you know that's one the second
is of course people culture will largely
be you know benefited from that right in
the beginning
a third is the point that you're making
the initial 4a i mean if you look at
isis lombard we started largely with
corporate business
we started writing more much later and
that also we
you know we leverage the bank's oem
relationship to get into
get an entry right so you're absolutely
right that we
benefited tremendously from the uh
bank's presence
uh particularly in that point in time
bank was very strong in the retail asset
side right
and in terms of the auto loans etc so
any dealer would
know icc bank and you know and we had a
uh
advantage but over the years that's kind
of
you know kind of uh now thereafter you
have to build on our own so for example
the agency channel is unique to
insurance right that's not something
that you can build from um
from the icg bank platform uh bank
assurance we heard the advantage of icc
bank but because of isis bank we
couldn't go to other banks
till sometime you know then gradually
people began to trust that you know
these guys
you know are trustable so i can give
them my vacations business so that's
changed over the years
but initially that was a bit of a
challenge so uh
so we had a tremendous advantage today
that now that
if you look at our share of business
that we get from icc bank is now down to
you know six seven percent uh and the
distribution channel for example the
uh two wheeler where we build a dominant
pleasant presence
we've kind of helped the bank go in
there because two lending wasn't a big
piece for the bank so now it's i mean
that you know the parent advantage of
course remains as many benefits that we
get
but it's not as much as in the beginning
so last question vargas before
you go um the typical person uh
listening in today uh
i reckon typical person listening today
will have an income of around a crore
right now we do position sizing as fund
managers but honestly we have no idea
how much should somebody earning one
crore in india how much health cover
should that person buy right and
honestly even i do it on guesswork
so some professional input for everybody
listening on how much health cover
should the sort of people who are
listening in suppose they're earning one
crude per annum how much health cover
should they buy
so i would look uh i would say that a
profile of your you know investors here
should buy a deductible plan a
deductible plan is not a grounds up plan
a deductible plan is to say that you
know your first let's say three or five
lakh you'll pay out of your pocket uh
and then buy
a one crore cover at least a 50 lakh
count
right because and and if you really want
absolute peace of mind you know buy a
cover that covers for global treatment
and go for a few crores you know three
four pros right
um why do i say first deductible you
know
look i think anyone who's earning five
one crore can spend two three lakhs in a
in a crisis right not a big deal but if
you do that your cost of
insurance really comes down right uh and
the other thing that you should buy
increasingly coming you know as i said
it wasn't there in the market is the
outpatient cover because
uh there is tremendous aggregation
benefit that we get as an insurance
player when you buy out patient car you
know this is not there in the market
very not very popular
you know some of us have launched it but
it's not very popular but buy a top-up
cover with the first deductible and a
opt cover which takes care of your
regular doctor visits and all these
other things
because there's a tremendous benefit
that you get in terms of costly
i'm glad i asked the question i learned
a lot myself thank you very much vargas
this was fabulous
we'll continue with our clients with
some you know housekeeping work thank
you sir we learned a lot
best of luck in growing at 23 fat
because we have a vested interest in
that thank you thank you so much thank
you for having me bye-bye
so page over to you yeah sure
okay you might want to switch off the
camera because i think there's a bit of
low bandwidth at your end so you might
want to switch off the camera especially
since you'll be projecting as well
so folks will focus today page will
focus today on uh
in the last month or so data has come
through on how quickly the kings of
capital
lenders are growing in in spite of the
the mayhem
that we've seen in the broader country
so we'll focus on the growth rate of the
lenders
and why we remain convinced that these
lenders will carry on
doing very well or in spite of the
second wave so over to youth
there are three factors rising in the
growth of the indian lending industry
the first factor being that the indian
banking sector
usually grows at a multiplier of the gdp
uh
so historically over the past 10 years
we've seen that
the indian banking sector grow about two
things
gdp growth uh this again can be divided
into two phases
up to 2014 up to 2050. uh
the growth were about three times
however over the past three four years
because of
a variety of factors including asset
quality reviews
basis across multiple cycles from a
10-year period
in indian gain sector credit growth is
usually around
two times of real gdp growth
the second factor which is an additional
layer of growth on top of
the banking sector growth is that
private sector banks grow at a further
multiplier of the
banking sector credit growth so in kings
of capital we have not invested in any
public sector lenders we have invested
only in private sector lenders
therefore this is very relevant for the
kings of capital portfolio
so in addition to the real gdp growth
multiplier there is a 1.75 times
multiplier for the private sector banks
so if you look at the chart
on the right of the screen we've seen
that banking sector credit growth while
it has been much more volatile
it has been impacted a lot
because of the asset quality review and
then demonetization and the s bank
crisis we've seen that even during the
past five years
the private banking sector credit growth
has been around the 19 20
mark uh because india's
public sector banks still account for 60
65 percent of the market
we've seen that the sector credit growth
over the past five years has slowed down
but because for us the more relevant
metric is the rate at which private
sector banks in india have grown
so even during the past five years where
the macro was challenging especially for
the financial sector
you've seen that uh credit growth for
the private banks was
at around 19 20 and this is largely
because of
market share gains from the psu banks uh
so we've we've seen that only over the
past five years we've seen that
uh market share of private sector banks
went up from about 25 percent
to 40 so straight 15 jump in market
share over the past five years
uh in addition to these two factors
we've seen that even within the private
sector there are a select few players
who are able to rapidly benefit and
rapidly grow their profits
from this unique opportunity so we've
taken the examples of hdfc bank
bank bajaj finance which are able to
disproportionately benefit
this unique opportunity that the indian
banking sector provides
opportunity being first of all india
because
it is a developing economy credit is
underpenetrated it is a credit star
economy the banking sector credit grows
at a multiplier of real gdp
second because private sector banks
still account for only 30 35 40 percent
of market share
they grow even more rapidly than the
banking sector credit cards
uh and within the private sector we've
seen that
the success of these players depends on
three things one is
all lenders have a high reinvestment
rate so we've seen
jfc code of bajaj finance reinvestment
rate consistently in excess of 80
percent
second when these lenders reinvest
capital
they reinvest along with the equity
also leverage which is raised on top of
the equity capital
so for example if say a lender owns a
profit in any given year of 100 rupees
and 90 percent is the reinvestment rate
so 90 rupees will be reinvested in the
business
in addition to the 90 rupees of equity
which will be reinvested
because lenders are a leveraged business
they'll also reinvest say if a lender is
leveraged 10 times they'll also reinvest
900 rupees of
debt into the business so not only is
there a higher investment rate in terms
of equity but there is a further
reinvestment of debt on top of that
equity
secondly uh on top of that these lenders
generate a consistently high return on
assets so on the total amount which
which is being invested by these lenders
debt plus equity they are able to
consistently generate return on assets
they are able to do this because of a
variety of reasons which we have
highlighted earlier simple such finance
hdfc bank because of their superior
technology technological and big data
capabilities
uh similarly quota miner bank because of
its superior capital allocation
capabilities
has been able to consistently generate
return on asset
in between four percent on this high
amount of reinvested capital
uh and the ultimate result of this is
the chart on the right of the screen
that over the past 50 years
we have seen that uh hdfc product bank
or bajaj finance they've been able to
consistently grow profits at
20 25 30 percent uh so the
factors which these lenders have
benefited from are high reinvestment
rate
ability to leverage on the higher
reinvestment rate
by raising external capital at lower
cost of funds and thirdly on that by
generating
consistently higher return on assets on
this free invested capital
coming to growth during these
challenging times
during
so why don't you stop projecting i'll
i'll project so perhaps that will help
help your voice come through perhaps if
you stop projecting
it'll use uh yeah so i'll just i'll just
do the projection
so that way perhaps we can save some
bandwidth just to give me one minute
and i'll beam up the slides uh
here we go yeah
so back to youtube
please can you hear me
okay i think uh i think we've lost uh
you can see the slides right
i can see this line yeah so just carry
on i'll get try to put this in
show mode one second
yeah just they just carry on with the
projection i'll try to put this in show
mode
uh yes uh so
coming to the growth in q4 and q3
uh we've seen that during the lockdown
the lenders in our portfolio had become
conservative
that slowed down growth because there
was more visibility on
cash flows of their borrowers there was
lower visibility on how
the kovid impact will eventually pan out
however especially during the december
and march quarters we seeing that
the lenders have started accelerating
growth so growth has
growth had normalized in the december
quarter and they are actually
in uh they are actually above
pre-covered levels in terms of quarterly
unqueue growth
by the end of the march quarter so while
the industry
in the december quarter was growing at
only 10 percent
the kcp lenders were growing at almost
twice that rate
of 18 during q4 again the industry
we believe will be growing at only 10 12
but the lenders in the kings of capital
portfolio
will grow they've grown at around 27 28
percent
so this market share phenomenon the
gaining market share
things of capital lenders gaining market
share this is something which is likely
to continue
over the next three four years and the
reasons for these this market share
gains are pretty obvious
these are lenders which are well
capitalized uh these are lenders which
have access
year one capital these are the lenders
which have provided well for
uh the povid uh ntls which will come
through
not only the first wave but also
partially for the second cohort wave nps
which are
likely to come through in the coming
quarters uh
and these lenders are likely to grow at
the 20
plus mark over the next three four five
years
just like they had grown before kobe
these market share gains are likely to
accelerate
in the coming few years so could you
move to the next slide please
yeah uh when we look at the balance
sheet position of these lenders
we are able to see that the npa's
increased from
about one point seven one point eight
percent before covet
so in the december quarter the npas for
the portfolio
at a median level were around one point
eight percent despite what was expected
of overheat that there will be
a huge surge in nps we've seen that the
nps have been pretty manageable
nps are at only about two and a half
percent
uh on this increased uh marginal
increase in npas
the provision coverage ratio has come to
now about eighty percent for the lenders
in our portfolio
before covet this was about 50 percent
uh and now it is at about 80 so despite
the increase in nps despite the increase
in provision coverage ratios
we are seeing that the tr1 for the
lenders
is now higher than what it used to be
before
uh the tier one capital for the lenders
in our portfolio now stands at around 21
this number used to be at around 18
percent before
uh and this is the reason why the
lenders in our portfolio will be able to
absorb
any additional nps which will come
through because of the second coveted
wave
uh and also in case there is a third
port wave these lenders will
be able to absorb those sort of nps and
then we'll be able to recover and land
when whenever the credit demand recovers
over the next few quarters
uh finally coming to performance we
launched in july 2020
so uh it's been about nine ten months
since we launched
uh this these are numbers in absolute
terms twenty four percent
since inception uh versus about forty
five percent for the bank nifty
uh and the reason uh that there seems to
be a large difference between the bank
nifty and the portfolio is
that the bank nifty consists only of
banks uh it consists primarily of five
banks
five banks being uh hdfc codec
access ics and sbi these five banks form
about 90 percent of the bank nifty
uh versus uh in our portfolio we have
about 35 to 14 percent in non lenders
the likes of isis lombard hdfc life a
couple of other players
and we also have nbfcs uh if we were to
compare the performance of lenders
versus the bank nifty
we are at around 40 to 43 percent versus
the bank nifty that about 45 46
however because uh since we launched
uh since july the non-lenders in the
portfolio did not see
a large drawdown due to the first covert
view they were actually beneficiaries
of the poverty vape just like we heard
from bhargava icici lombard has actually
benefited from
it there was not a large drawdown in the
non-lenders
so the non-linking piece of the
portfolio has delivered around 9 10
percent of a return
while the lenders have delivered almost
similar returns as the bank nifty
and that is why it currently looks like
there is a big difference between
where the bank nifty is versus where our
portfolio is at
and folks one of the reasons we thought
one of the reasons we thought we should
invite bhargav is
so that others also appreciate why it's
worth having a financials portfolio
where 40 percent is non-lenders right
why
run a kings of capital portfolio where
uh uh we have the best life insurer the
best general insurer
the largest asset manager and the
largest stock broking player
because the savings theme in india is
incredibly powerful
as those anecdotes bhargav gave about
about one in two drivers not having a
third party cover
about the insur the health insurance
penetration being one-tenth
of china even though our per capita
income is only our capital income is
one-fifth of china
but our insurance purchase health cover
purchases one-tenth
so there's a massive story there on
savings which is playing out in fact
all of you all of us this evening are
part of the saving story
why else would you guys be listening to
a a presentation by a pms provider
we want to play that it gives us solid
compounding uh iloms 20
23 pack over a 13-14 year period where
the insurance profit pool
shrank is great proof of that and
remember the marcellus obsession what is
our obsession in life
we want to help our clients compound
consistently at 20 25
honestly other than these presentations
i don't even know what the nifty has
delivered or the bank nifty has
delivered
it really doesn't form too much of our
thinking underperformed
outperformed our goal is to put on the
table
as consistently as we can across all our
various products
at 20 25 return and we think having a
financials portfolio which is 60 high
quality lenders
40 savings place gets us to this number
of 2025 with a very high degree of
consistency which is why we are
happy very very happy with the portfolio
and have no reason to
change it uh uh we'll be happily
underperforming any index you give us
uh for the rest of our lives if we can
keep gunning out
20 25 so i'll stop the sharing here
and and go back uh let me just take a
few questions from
uh the the questions you guys are firing
and we'll try to do justice to that
um and hopefully it will give you a
sense of where kings of capital is going
by the way
assets under management in this
portfolio now are significantly north of
400 crores
and as states says we believe the next
two three years will bring plenty of
good news here in terms of underlying
eps compounding
uh what the stock market will do we
don't know at many levels we don't care
what we
try to specialize in is what will the
investee companies do
so so let's let's uh take a question
that sanji gupta is asking
so he's asking us how much conviction do
you have and
you have the privilege of answering this
question how much
conviction do you have that hdfc bank
will become a one trillion company
in ten years so it's today around 104
105 billion
so sanji gupta is asking what what
conviction do you have that will give
you 10x in 10 years
yeah so like
there is enough room for a bank say like
hdf night
to keep going for the next 10 years so
runway for growth elements
uh because like we showed on the slides
uh
first of all gdp growth in india is you
know
in real terms around say four five six
percent
on top of that there is a multiple
speaking sector related growth it goes
around 10 11
and the private sector uh banking
is around 14 15 um
despite the past 20 years for
compounding by hdfc bank despite it
growing at
825 over the past 20 years it still only
gets
seven seven eight percent sort of market
share in the indian banking industry
so runway for growth in terms of
whether it can take away market share
for most of the players
uh because 60 65 percent of the market
is still controlled by
these use uh we believe that the psu
banking
the psu banks because they have only
said 10 11 capital adequacy
the staff in terms of
so let me just take it there because i
think page's voice is breaking what
they're just trying to say is that
if you look at the well-run private
sector banks they're normally able to
grow their loan books
the overall private sector lending book
in totality grows at around 2x
gdp growth so if gdp growth in our
country nominal gdp growth this is
say ends up being seven eight percent i
think you're losing your voice
uh you might want to see if you can log
on because you're losing your voice
so private sector bank loan books should
grow at 2x gdp
so private sector bank totality 16 17
should be doable hdfc bank consistently
gains market share you can see that over
the last 12 months
over the last 12 months rbi has said
fifth five six percent
credit growth in the country hdfc bank
credit growth has been 17 18 percent
so hdfc bank consistently gains market
share even in the context
of private sector lenders it should be
able to do 20 percent loan growth
compounding
uh profits grow a little faster than
that
you should be ending up seeing 20 to 23
profit growth
and and sanjeevji even if you assume no
relating d rating
uh profit growth of 20 25 loan book
growth of around 20 percent
should give get hdfc bank to that to
that trillion dollar number
page was saying hdfc banks market share
is all of six percent just imagine
created in 1995 uh uh today six percent
market share 105 billion dollar market
cap
uh uh the public sector banks account
for 60
i imagine the growth runway therefore
for hdfc bank
i think there's another question by rk
gupta gupta
he's asking he's saying hi saurabh um i
i think he's referring to ilong
i say lombard one of the best companies
in general insurance growing at twenty
four percent kaggard
growing packed at 24 kagan but why is
the same
uh not reflecting in the share price why
has the share price just doubled in the
last four years right
so i think that's a happy situation
gupta we as investors in ilom are buying
lots of it
and we obviously will carry on buying it
page if you can hear me
do you want to comment on why ilom has
just doubled in the last four years in
terms of share price
yeah am i audible now yeah you're
audible now
okay uh so over the past four years
we've seen that isis lombard has
continued to deliver
20 in terms of return on equity
profit growth also has come through
uh and we've seen that
this has happened with other companies
as well uh even in the financial sector
say hdfc banks example if you were to
take
uh there have been periods where
uh the share price performance is not
uh exactly in sync with profit growth
however if we were to take a longer time
period
and we have seen that happen with all
our portfolios
uh including when we have back tested
the kings of capital portfolio as well
we've seen that
more than 80 to 90 percent of the share
price is attributed to earnings growth
uh so the differential in uh
share price growth and profit growth
usually over a period of time
is minimal it is very unlikely that a
company continues to grow profits at
around 20 percent
and its share price compounding would be
say at 10 percent so we believe that
the the gap between uh profit growth and
share price growth
over a period of time usually narrows
down uh it's a matter of time that that
happens
now now hari kalyan asks a question
which i think is he's asked it in the
context of isis lombard i think but i
think it's relevant for other
the rest of the kings of capital
portfolios as well including the lenders
so hari kalyan is saying
as warren buffett remarks if insurance
is more of a commodity how do you
differentiate
from the rest of the competition to earn
profits uh
is it through premium sales through
investments or anything else i think
perhaps you intended the question to be
asked by asked
of so i think it's worth explaining how
firms like hdfc life in the context of
life i love in the context of general
insurance
and say bajaj finance in the context of
nbfc
how these firms are building
quasi-monopolistic businesses that it's
very difficult for others
to compete with them on an even footing
and why the perception that it's a
commodity
is actually just that the reality is
that on our these firms are on their way
to building
incredibly powerful uh long-term growth
engines i'll just beam up the islam roe
numbers whilst you talk page
over to you so
from the outside it looks like there is
not
much of a differentiation when we look
at say isis
or any other jungle in charge because
eventually what they are selling is a
simple
simple insurance policy uh similarly if
you look at bajaj finance
all they are giving out is a simple loan
which any other lender which has capital
on its balance sheet can give up
however the biggest differentiation uh
between
bajaj finance or hdfc life or an isis
alarm part versus any other player in
the industry is
their investments in technology big data
analytics and the way that they think
about the next three four five years
it is pretty easy for a nbfc or a bank
to give out loans
to a salaried employee or even to a
self-employed employee
a self-employed individual however the
difference lies in
whether they are able to build
competitive advantages
over a long period of time uh by
building either
big big data analytics platforms which
have big data and analytics attached to
them
or by building large databases they
capture data
and they are able to predict uh whether
in the case of isis a lombard
there will be any adverse claims
in the future in the case of bajaj
finance whether the npas are likely to
rise
by giving a loan to a specific
individual because these companies
are started doing this i said
bargain experience started doing this
four five six years ago
uh bajaj finance has had started doing
this five stick seven years ago
because they are well ahead of
competition in terms of building
data analytics and big data capabilities
uh these are the companies which
keep on incrementally benefiting from
the big data and analytical capabilities
so if you were to take bajaj finances
example
because it already has a database of
about five six crore individuals in
india
it is able to lend to these individuals
much better than any other and we have
in india
because it is able to select individuals
which
are the least likely to default over the
next say one to three years
its big data capabilities and its
database keeps on improving even further
so for any other competitor of a bajaj
finance i say
lombard or hdfc life to play catch up
incrementally
keeps on becoming becoming more and more
difficult
so from the outside it looks like these
guys are doing anything something which
is completely ordinary
uh which can which has a lot of
competition
however when we look at returns and
equity of these players
we are seeing that we'll seeing that on
the screen the returns on equity are 20
or 20 percent plus because they've
invested in intangibles like big data
analytics
uh predictive capabilities which other
competitors have not been able to
so folks this point is actually really
central right the whole
rise of big data ai ml
the application of uh ai to big data
and the the virtuous cycle that it
creates
uh 20 years ago that wasn't there so if
you look at
uh why warren buffett made so much money
in geico and he's still one he's still
invested in geico so it's in any book on
buffett you'll
see that in what 1952 or 53. he invested
in geico it was a
he turned it under when bakshath took it
over 10-15 years later
they turned it around and geico became
one of the most profitable insurers
that dynamic the traditional
warren buffett cuff float while our
discourse turning around
loss making insurers running them
profitable making a lot of money
that was around sensible underwriting
judicious prudent
underwriting and sensible reinvestment
mother float
using buffett's investment acumen right
that dimensions been there and and and
and even through the 80s 90s
smart insurance executives knew that if
they were judicious
conservative in their policy
underwriting and
a wise in their
investments they could build a
profitable general insurer
last 20 years and especially in the last
10 years the additional dynamic that has
come in
is the ability to use data and ai
to build massive barriers to entry right
so admiral in the uk
uh uh so rakshas and i when we're in the
uk we used to cover admiral
admiral in the uk pioneered it right
they were born around the turn of the
turn of the century and by 2006
i was a massive player who was one of
the largest insurance underwriters motor
insurance underwriters so from
scratch from scratch in a decade to
building a
a giant insurance business using online
and and unconventional but
very clever underwriting using uzamanika
big data turn of the century big data
firms like ilom forms like hdfc life uh
we recommend doing it in another level
and this self-reunific spiral is very
powerful that's why we were asking
bhargav whether he will become a
consolidator and i think
politely he told us he will and
therefore we stand to make a lot of
money
as as i long goes on to monopolize the
insurance
it's very very difficult to see why in
life insurance
and in general insurance uh 10 to 20
years out
we won't have you know far fewer players
than we have today
and why well-run efficient franchises
like hdfc live and ilom
won't make lots of money for for
marcellus and marcellus's clients
so i think we'll leave it at that today
folks thank you very much for joining in
i hope
you found the session useful i will keep
trying to bring these sorts of uh
ceos to you and i think in in in our
other portfolios as well
uh the same initiatives are underway to
bring to you the great promoters the
great ceos
who drive compounding to drive wealth
for our clients we are
basically just custodians of your money
the real work the real
brilliance is uh you know 30 management
teams who run india's best businesses
so you'll see uh you'll you'll see more
uh
emails from us going out to you inviting
you to join
more such webinars with india's best
ceos thank you very much for joining us
today
take care stay safe